Beppie L. Culin papers, 1801-1985 (bulk 1923-1970)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Beppie L. Culin papers, 1801-1985 (bulk 1923-1970)
MS 380
Culin, Beppie L.
This collection consists of the papers of Beppie L. Culin and family. Correspondence, diaries, scrapbooks, photographs, and legal documents are included in this collection.
.5 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None
Biographical Note
Beppie Lee Leslie Culin was born August 10th, 1887 in Honolulu, Hawaii. Her parents were Harry Melville Leslie and Sallie Knox Wood. Beppie Lee Leslie was married on December 19, 1913 to John Harding Culin (1889-1925), who was a Lieutenant Commander in the United States Navy. John H. Culin died on March 20, 1925 of malaria while in Port-au-Prince, Haiti. Beppie L. Culin never remarried and lived in Tucson, Arizona until her death in March 1988.
Scope and Content Note
This collection consists of the papers of Beppie L. Culin and family. Correspondence, diaries, scrapbooks, photographs, and legal documents are included in this collection. The majority of the correspondence is between Beppie L. Culin and various offices of the United States Navy regarding the death of John H. Culin and his subsequent reinterment at Arlington National Cemetery. Also included is correspondence to J.F. McKale and Richard A. Harvill of the University of Arizona regarding alumnus information and activities. This collection contains two diaries of John H. Culin, which contain a brief account of his daily activities from 1918-1919. The scrapbook in the collection contains ship logs, poetry, drawings and newspaper clippings on various topics, including the War of 1812.
The photographs in this collection include several photographs of Beppie L. Culin, as well as John H. Culin. Also included are portraits of unidentified females and various pictures of people and places, including property at Martha?™s Vineyard.
This collection also contains legal documents including a land patent signed by US President Andrew Jackson in 1831, and two bills of sale for slaves sold to John S. Wood. The first bill of sale is for an 11-year-old slave girl sold on February 28, 1852, and the second bill of sale is for an 18-year-old slave boy sold on February 13, 1854.
Access Terms
Culin, Beppie L. -- Archives
Culin, John Harding
United States. Navy -- History -- 20th century
Sailors' writings, English
Slaves -- Legal status, laws, etc. -- United States
Bills of sale --United States
Correspondence
Diaries
Photographs
Scrapbooks
Land patents
Container List
- Correspondence, 1923-1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1966-1985 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Documents regarding Beppie L. Culin, 1910-1936; No Date (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Diaries of John H. Culin, 1918-1919 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Documents regarding John H. Culin, 1923-1926; No Date (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Scrapbook, 1801-1857 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Documents regarding the Pauline M. Roskruge Estate, 1923-1937 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Documents regarding Beppie L. Culin's family, 1924-1985; No Date (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Photographs of Beppie L. Culin, 1971-1982 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Photographs of John H. Culin, 1912; No Date (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Portraits of unidentified females, No Date (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Photographs of people and places, including property at Martha's Vineyard, 1976-1981; No Date (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Land documents, including a land patent signed by US President Andrew Jackson in 1831, 1831-1836 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Bills of sale for slaves; including a bill of sale for an 11-year-old slave girl to John S. Wood in 1852 and a bill of sale for an 18-year-old slave boy to John Wood in 1854, 1852-1854 (Box 1, Folder 14)